你就没有个工作吗
Don't you have a job or something?
有啊  自由货船
Yeah, on a freelance cargo ship.
我们跑香港  西班牙  布宜诺斯艾利斯
We go to Hong Kong, Spain,
总之就是老板让去哪  我们就去哪
Buenos Aires, basically wherever the boss tells us.
败家子一个
Corrupt son of a bitch.
我们触发了一些事
We've awoken something,
一些被极力掩盖的关于迈克尔的事
something people are trying to hide about Michael.
这个波塞冬到底是何方神圣
Who the hell is this Poseidon guy?
一个变态
A psychopath.
中情局里一名不得志的政策专家
A frustrated policy wonk
他在中情局内创建了
in the CIA who created a cell
一个叫"21号空间"的组织
within the CIA called 21-Void.
他们需要我的帮助
And they needed my help
卡尼尔·乌提斯
系ISIL恐怖分子
因杀害一名中情局高级官员
并制造多起爆炸案
而被中情局通缉
卡尼尔·乌提斯
系ISIL恐怖分子
因杀害一名中情局高级官员
并制造多起爆炸案
而被联调局通缉
在世界各地帮人越狱
breaking out people in prison all over the world.
在凯勒曼被杀之前
Before he was killed,
他一直在调查"21号空间"这个组织
Kellerman had been looking into 21-Void.
我需要你查明
I need you to look into the possibility
机密  仅供过目
是否可能有内部人员牵涉其中
that there was an insider involved.
没想到这个时间打电话过来
I wasn't expecting a call at this hour.
我觉得我们得尽快见面
I think we need to meet soon.
我在看那个人去哪了
I was looking for where the man went.
什么人  宝贝
What man, baby?
给我这个的人
The man that gave me this.
迈克尔
Michael.
你陷入了什么麻烦呢
What are you into?
你只要告诉我们要去哪
Just tell us where you're headed.
穿越沙漠483公里  到费阿刻斯
300 miles across the desert, Phaeacia.
自治领地  没有ISIL的人
Autonomous zone. No ISIL.
我可以带你们去
I can lead you there.
费阿刻斯  我们找到了
Phaeacia, we found it!
在城里  我就告诉过你你会死
Back in the city, I told you you would die.
迈克尔
Michael.
他给我下了毒
He poisoned me.
你画画好得简直不可思议  麦克
It's incredible how good you've gotten at drawing, Mike.
真的  太...
Really, that's...
太棒了
that's so good.
画的是个希腊英雄
It's a Greek hero.
他看着好像受伤了
He looks hurt.
他们早晚都会受伤
They all get hurt sooner or later.
这就是希腊英雄的伟大之处
That's what's great about Greek heroes,
他们是真实的  不像超人
they're real, not supermen.
他们会受伤
They get hurt.
会死去
They can die.
对不住了  哥们  忍着点
Hey, I'm sorry, buddy, last little bit.
我得把伤口清理干净
I got to keep it clean, you know?
不过看着好多了
It's looking much better though, okay?
你表现得很好  再坚持一下 哥们
You're doing good. You just hang in there, buddy.
怎么样了
How we doing?
有办法了
Got something.
我们那边的朋友有条船
Our friend over there has a boat.
他要走私去希腊
He's making a smuggling run to Greece.
他说他能带你弟弟去看"第一世界"的医生[美欧等发达国家]
He says he can take your brother to a First World doctor.
"第一世界"以为他是卡尼尔·乌提斯
First world thinks he's Kaniel Outis.
他们会就地逮捕他的
They'll arrest him on sight.
那怎么办
So?
还有得选吗  让他等死吗
What's the alternative, let him die?
你怎么当哥哥的
What kind of a brother are you?
你要是再说这种屁话
You say something like that again,
我发誓  我会杀了你
I swear to God, I'll kill you.
也许有第三种选择
There might be a third option.
回去上班的第一天  感觉怎么样
So how was your first day back?
我不得不说  对着一帮18岁孩子的头顶
I have to say, it's never been so rewarding
讲博弈论  而他们却低头
to teach game theory to the tops
忙着给彼此发信息玩"文爱"[挑逗性文字]
of a bunch of 18-year-olds' heads
从来没有让我这么满足过
while they're busy sexting each other.
但是
But...
正常生活也叫嚣着回归了
normalcy's threatening to come back,
为此干一杯吧
and I say cheers to that.
干杯
Cheers to that.
走  咱们到外面坐坐
Come on, let's sit outside.
我这就过去
I'll be right there.
喂
Hello?
我们找到迈克尔了
We found Michael.
是我们的迈克尔吗
Is he our Michael?
是的  莎拉
Yes, Sara.
莎拉  听好  他被下毒了
Sara, listen, he's been poisoned.
估计是防冻液
We think it's antifreeze.
他失血过多
He's lost a lot of blood.
需要很多血
He needs a lot of blood.
好的  如果是防冻液的话他需要很多东西
Okay. He needs a lot of things if it's antifreeze.
听我说
Listen, uh,
我们要去希腊
we're heading to Greece.
有没有什么办法能让我们用些非法药物救他
Is there any way we can get some medical help off the books?
不行  不行  这种情况下
No, no, no, no, no, this isn't the kind of thing
用非法药物肯定不成
that you want to do off the books.
听好  林肯  他需要输血
Listen, Lincoln, he's gonna need a transfusion.
迈克尔是B型阴性血型
Michael's B negative, okay?
可能只有百分之一的人是那种血型
It's maybe one percent of the population with that blood type.
你们去的地方找不到这种血型
You won't find it where you're going,
你找的时候他也撑不住的
and he won't make it while you look.
除非给你送上门
Unless it comes to you.
我等下给你回电话
I'll call you back.
什么事
Hey, what's going on?
我
I, uh...
我得走了
I got to go.
你得走了吗
You got to go?
去哪
‭Go where?
去克里特岛
To Crete.
迈克尔
Michael, um,
他们找到他了
they found him.
他还活着
He's alive.
他中毒了
He's poisoned.
-迈克尔  你的前任迈克尔吗  -是的
- Michael? Your ex, Michael? - Yeah.
等等  等一下
Wait, hold on a second,
他真的还活着吗
he really is alive?
他刚刚联系过你
He contacted you just now?
是的  他需要帮助
Yeah, and, uh, and he needs help,
我认为我是唯一一个能帮他的人
and I think I'm the only one that can help him.
我坐飞机能比他们坐船先到
Yeah, I can get there faster on a plane than they can on a boat.
等等  莎拉
Whoa, whoa, whoa, Sara?
你... 你并不亏欠他什么
Y-You don't owe him that.
连你自己都不知道会陷入什么麻烦中  这不安全
Y-You don't know what you'd be walking into; it's not safe.
我会没事的  我别无选择
I'll be fine. I don't have a choice.
我... 这真是糟糕的一周
I...this has been a hell of a week.
好吧  我知道你有大把大把的疑问
Okay, look, I know you've got a million questions,
我也一样  好吗
just like I do, okay?
我不能直视着我儿子的眼睛
I can't look my son in the eye
告诉他我本来可以尽力救他父亲
and tell him that I let his father die
但我却让他死了
when I could've tried to save him;
虽然他还从没见过他父亲  我做不到
A father he's never met. I can't do that.
如果我跟你说别去呢
And if I told you not to go?
"如果"可不是随便说的
"If" is a big word in that sentence.
雅各布  你是在要求我别去吗
Jacob, are you telling me not to go?
不
No.
不  当然不是
No, of course not.
好的
Okay.
本该让她置身事外的  林肯
Should've left her out of this, Linc.
闭嘴  你就要见到你七年未见的
Shut up. You're about to see the wife you haven't seen
老婆了
in seven years.
-我来  我来  -起航吧
- I got you, I got you. - Cast off.
你们准备好了
You're ready.
这话什么意思
What do you mean?
被关久了  久到我都记不清了
Been locked up for longer than I can remember.
奥杰吉亚之前  是我的公寓  脑袋和电话
Before Ogygia, it was my apartment, my head and my phone.
我周围都是高墙
Walls all around me.
看不到这个世界
Couldn't see the world.
我喜欢这里
I like it here.
没有高墙
No walls.
自由  我已经很长时间没体会过了
Freedom, like I haven't had in a long time.
我可以重新开始新的生活
I can start over.
除非你说你需要我
And unless you say you need me,
否则我想留下来
I'd like to stay.
你是自由的人  雅
You're a free man, Ja.
你决定吧
The choice is yours.
我欠你一条命
I owe you my life.
你把世界还给了我
You gave me back the world.
要帮他康复  给他平安啊
Get him healthy. Get safe.
我会的
Yeah, I will.
再见
See you.
我得知道
I got to know,
你真的有佛莱迪·摩克瑞的骨灰吗
you really got Freddie Mercury's ashes?
凯思·理查德吸了他死去父亲的骨灰是真的吗
Is it true Keith Richard snorted his dead father's ashes?
我不知道
I don't know.
正是如此
Exactly.
要活下去
Keep alive.
你也是  兄弟
You too, man.
林肯
Linc,
离希腊还有多远
how far is it to Greece?
十二个小时
12 hours.
莎拉会在十二个小时后赶到那
Sara's gonna be there in 12.
我觉得我撑不了十二个小时了
I don't think I have 12 hours in me.
m 211 -8 b 217 -6 217 -4 217 -2 l 217 24 b 217 26 217 29 211 31 l 31 31 b 26 29 26 26 26 24 l 26 -2 b 26 -4 26 -6 31 -8
m 20 0 l 209 0 b 218 0 229 11 229 20 l 229 209 b 229 218 218 228 209 228 l 20 228 b 11 228 0 218 0 209 l 0 20 b 0 11 11 0 20 0
m 115 64 l 115 35 l 171 0 l 177 0 l 133 46 l 143 52 l 179 0 l 184 0 l 159 63 l 229 107 l 229 182 l 145 96 l 135 122 l 207 227 l 137 227 l 115 172 l 115 93 l 126 76 l 115 64 l 104 76 l 115 93 l 115 172 l 93 227 l 23 227 l 95 122 l 84 96 l 0 182 l 0 107 l 70 63 l 45 0 l 50 0 l 87 52 l 97 46 l 52 0 l 59 0 l 115 35
m 71 60 b 71 0 161 0 161 60 b 161 120 71 120 71 60
m 325 0 l 355 0 l 332 47 l 354 47 l 399 136 l 369 136 l 328 53 l 288 136 l 257 136 l 325 0 m 467 0 l 497 0 l 474 47 l 496 47 l 541 136 l 511 136 l 470 53 l 430 136 l 399 136 l 467 0 m 545 1 l 583 1 l 583 14 l 568 14 l 568 19 l 583 19 l 583 30 l 568 30 l 568 34 l 599 34 l 599 30 l 583 30 l 583 19 l 599 19 l 599 14 l 583 14 l 583 1 l 611 1 b 616 1 622 6 622 10 l 622 36 l 652 0 l 678 0 l 644 41 l 622 41 l 622 47 l 596 47 l 597 54 l 625 54 l 625 68 l 541 68 l 541 54 l 572 54 l 571 47 l 545 47 l 545 1 m 583 72 l 583 85 l 569 85 l 569 90 l 598 90 l 598 85 l 583 85 l 583 72 l 611 72 b 615 72 621 78 621 82 l 653 44 l 678 44 l 644 86 l 621 86 l 621 103 l 597 103 l 597 136 l 570 136 l 564 126 l 562 136 l 542 136 l 548 107 l 568 107 l 565 121 l 571 121 l 571 103 l 547 103 l 547 72 l 583 72 m 600 107 l 620 107 l 624 124 l 653 89 l 679 89 l 642 136 l 615 136 l 618 132 l 606 132 l 600 107 m 689 0 l 716 0 l 721 15 l 732 15 l 732 30 l 718 56 l 731 56 l 735 100 l 721 100 l 717 59 l 714 64 l 714 136 l 693 136 l 693 79 l 676 79 l 707 30 l 679 30 l 679 15 l 694 15 l 689 0 m 738 0 l 804 0 b 807 0 813 6 813 9 l 813 87 l 794 87 l 794 14 l 756 14 l 756 87 l 763 77 l 763 21 l 787 21 l 787 91 l 798 91 l 798 120 l 820 120 l 812 136 l 778 136 l 778 90 l 748 136 l 723 136 l 756 87 l 738 87 l 738 0 m 257 151 l 275 151 l 297 182 l 319 151 l 337 151 l 304 197 l 304 227 l 290 227 l 290 197 l 257 151 m 337 151 l 355 151 l 377 182 l 399 151 l 417 151 l 384 197 l 384 227 l 370 227 l 370 197 l 337 151 m 425 192 l 447 192 b 445 181 427 181 425 192 l 410 192 b 414 162 458 162 462 192 l 462 206 l 425 206 b 425 210 429 212 433 213 l 462 213 l 462 227 l 433 227 b 412 227 408 203 410 192 m 462 151 l 532 151 l 532 165 l 504 165 l 504 227 l 489 227 l 489 165 l 462 165 l 462 151 m 580 172 l 580 186 l 549 186 b 543 186 543 192 549 192 l 565 192 b 589 192 589 227 565 227 l 532 227 l 532 213 l 565 213 b 570 213 570 206 565 206 l 549 206 b 524 206 524 172 549 172 l 580 172 m 592 213 l 606 213 l 606 227 l 592 227 l 592 213 m 639 172 l 665 172 l 665 186 l 639 186 b 623 186 623 213 639 213 l 665 213 l 665 227 l 639 227 b 603 227 603 172 639 172 m 700 184 b 722 184 722 215 700 215 l 700 229 b 740 229 740 170 700 170 b 660 170 660 229 700 229 l 700 215 b 680 215 680 184 700 184 m 737 172 l 782 172 b 803 172 813 177 813 198 l 813 228 l 799 228 l 799 198 b 799 186 793 187 782 187 l 782 228 l 768 228 l 768 187 l 752 187 l 752 228 l 737 228 l 737 172
原创翻译  双语字幕
最新连载海外影视剧下载
请登陆 www.YYeTs.com
仅供交流学习  禁止商用盈利
m 38 -1 l 44 6 l 38 13 l 19 13 b 14 12 14 6 14 6 b 14 6 14 0 19 -1
m 200 -1 l 200 13 l 19 13 b 14 12 14 6 14 6 b 14 6 14 0 19 -1
翻译     高庭玫瑰   春天里的小熊   肉塔   轩辕喵
翻译     徐棒棒    木浅    普利星布里狗    匡老师
校对     木浅   匡老师想当网红   普利星布里狗
时间轴     姜姜    大葱    壬虚浪影    WEB版轴  何何、
越 狱 第五季第七集
后期     吉吉    V2版后期  、胜天半子、的、何何、
总监     & 校对      、胜天半子、的、何何、
越狱     我命由我不由天！胜天半子半痴癫！
缅因州  波特兰
我是对的  我们有麻烦了
I was right, we got problems.
显然  昨天我们去过国家安全局之后
Apparently, State Department is asking questions about 21-Void
国务院在打听"21号空间"了
after our visit to NSA yesterday.
他们没有可靠的情报
They have no viable information.
"21号空间"不存在
21-Void doesn't exist.
波塞冬会清理门户的
Poseidon will clean house.
麻烦不会消失
The problem's not going away.
那个国务院的探员想等我们一下飞机就见面
That State Department agent wants to meet as soon as we land.
伊拉克里翁国际机场
希腊  克里特岛
去哈尼亚
Chania, please?
谢谢
Thank you.
雅各布
我爱你  支持你  尽早回家
克里特岛  费尼卡斯
这里很安全
It is safe here.
我来时住在这
I use when I come.
能给他找点吃的吗
You got any food for him?
跟我来  在船里
Come, it's in the boat.
太好了  谢谢
Great, thank you.
让他保持清醒
Keep his spirits up.
没问题  伙计
All right, man.
天啊
Oh, man.
你得挺住啊  兄弟
Got to hang in there, buddy, huh?
你还得告诉我很多事  知道吗
Still got a lot of things to tell me, you know?
还要告诉我为什么我是你的得力干将
You gonna tell me why I'm your whip hand.
记得吗
Remember?
我对你  掏心掏肺  真心真意
I got a lot invested in you.
你现在不能死  迈克尔  知道吗
You can't die on me now, Michael, you know?
我刚刚叫了你迈克尔
Called you Michael.
我第一次知道你的真名
The first-- first time I ever really known your name,
即使如此  我也觉得...
even though I feel like...
从见面起我们就是好兄弟了  知道吗
I feel like we've been brothers since we met, you know?
但林肯来了
You know, with-- with Linc here...
我第一次觉得自己是个局外人
...it was the first time I ever felt like an outsider with you.
就像...
You know, like--
就像我失去了...
like I lost...
自己的一个家人
part of my family or something.
所以  迈克尔  你要明白  你不能死
So, you see, Michael, you can't die.
求你了
Please?
林肯
Linc.
我很想你
I missed you.
我会治好你的
I'm gonna fix you up.
然后我们好好聊  好吗
And then we'll talk, okay?
我会治好你的
I'm gonna make you okay.
不
No.
没事的
It's okay.
林肯
Hey, Lincoln, uh,
能把那边的衣帽架给我吗
would you pass me that coatrack?
-还有椅子  -好的
- Could I grab the chair, please? - Yeah.
谢谢
Thanks.
我们要给他输血
We'll do a transfusion.
我是O型阴性血
I'm O negative.
万能输血者
It's the universal donor.
这是除了他的血型外唯一能给他输的血型
Turns out it's the only other blood type I could've given him.
也许这就是命运吧
Maybe there's something to destiny, huh?
他会活下来吗
Is he gonna live?
是的
Yeah.
没错  他会活下来
Yeah, he'll live.
再给他几个小时时间
Give him a couple hours.
他很坚强
He's strong.
那我们给你点时间
We'll, uh... we'll give you a minute.
好的
Yeah.
我在这
I'm right here.
我就在这
我们得想办法离开这座岛
We need to work out a way to get off this island.
之前...
What I said...
我对你说的话
about you--
是我错了
I was wrong.
能有像你这样如此在乎家人的哥哥
A man would be lucky to have a brother
是一件幸运的事  你知道吗
cares as much as you, you know?
能得妻如此
Wife like that...
便是家的感觉
...family.
我可不觉得是因为幸运
I wouldn't call it luck.
我们一起出生入死
You've been through what we've been through.
我们现在也是家人了
You're family now.
为家人干杯
I'll drink to that.
好
Yeah.
坐飞机真的行不通了吗
Flying's really out of the question?
是的
Yeah.
机场比医院还糟
Airports are worse than hospitals.
一旦卡尼尔·乌提斯的名字被公开通缉
And once the name Kaniel Outis is radioactive,
他们就会对他格杀勿论
they'll shoot him on sight.
那么再找一艘船呢
So another boat?
渡过大西洋
Across the Atlantic?
我不是水手  但我知道那港口里
I'm no sailor, but I know that no boat in that harbor
没有船能带我们走那么远
is gonna get us that far.
我们需要一艘大船
We need a big boat.
不介意载通缉犯的大船
One that doesn't mind a radioactive cargo, you know?
雪城地方机场
我想继续我们之前的谈话
Hey there, I wanted to follow up on our conversation.
显然  中情局和国务院
Obviously, the CIA and State,
我们在共享卡尼尔·乌提斯的情报
we've been sharing information on Kaniel Outis,
但我想问的是
but my question for you is:
乌提斯杀了阿布·拉马尔
Outis killed Abu Ramal,
帮了国家一个大忙
did the country a service.
但你们昨天为什么还在国家安全局
So why were you still at NSA yesterday,
还想杀他
trying to kill him?
我们先离开停机坪行吗
Why don't we get off the tarmac?
我们会尽可能给你共享调查得来的情报
We'll share what we can about our investigation.
这都是官僚主义造成的信息误传
This is all just bureaucratic miscommunication.
我们可以消除误解
We can iron it out.
希望你们明白  我们同中情局核实过了
So you know, we checked with CIA.
中情局昨天并没有批准你们前往国安局
The CIA didn't sanction your visit to NSA yesterday.
甚至没人知道你们去了
No one even knew you were there.
你们究竟为谁卖命
Who are you working for, really?
你们为什么想解决卡尼尔・乌提斯
And why were you trying to take out Kaniel Outis?
没想到还能再见到你
Never thought I'd see this face again.
你本不应该见到的
You weren't supposed to.
为什么
Why?
我会一五一十地把整件事告诉你
I'll tell you everything you want to know.
但首先  我需要你给我个东西
But first, I need something from you.
什么都行
Anything.
一张我儿子的照片
A picture of my son.
我们昨天没去国安局
We weren't at NSA yesterday.
我告诉你  这是场误会
I'm telling you, this is a mistake.
对我撒谎也是个错误
And it's a mistake to lie to me.
我能让你们受到审判
I can have you prosecuted.
我在国安局的联系人给了我证据
I have a contact at the NSA and she gave me proof.
你不会叫他小麦吧
You're not calling him Junior, are you?
我保证过我不会那样叫他的
I promised you I would never do that.
他是个了不起的孩子
He's an amazing kid.
他就像你一样
He's just like you.
怎么了
What's wrong?
是他
It's him.
你的丈夫
Your husband.
-雅各布吗  -雅各布
- Jacob? - Jacob.
雅各布就是波塞冬
Jacob is Poseidon.
我就知道  我没疯
I knew it. I wasn't crazy.
他说谎被我抓了现行  但他...
I caught him lying, but he-he--
老天  他掩饰得太好了
oh, God, he covered it so well.
他表现得很真诚还受了伤  我就相信了他
He was... honest and hurt, and I bought it.
他是谁
Who is he?
到底是谁
Really?
他是中情局特工  深度卧底
He's a CIA operative, deep cover.
他管理着一个叫做"21号空间"的地下组织
He runs a splinter cell called 21-Void.
这和你有什么关系
What does this have to do with you?
他看中了我的能力
He targeted me for my skills,
要挟我
blackmailed me.
他说  如果我不同意为他效力
He told me if I didn't agree to come work for him,
他就不会放过你和林肯
he'd go after you and Linc,
把你俩都送进监狱
put you both in jail.
然后他用行动向我证明了他所言非虚
And then he proved it to me.
他说会让我再也见不到你俩
He said I could never see either one of you again.
或是麦克
Or Mike.
逼着我伪造了我的死亡
Made me fake my death.
然后他就利用我
And then he just used me.
他娶了我
He married me.
如果我早知道他就是你老公  我发誓...
If I'd known he was your husband, I swear...
不  不  不  这不怪你
No, no, no, no, no, this is not on you.
我...
I...
为什么现在  为什么现在回来
Why now? Why did you come back now?
那个纸鹤...
The origami...
四年前  他背叛了我
Four years ago, he betrayed me
现在我知道为什么了
and now I know why.
他想让我消失
He wanted me out of the way...
这样他就能拥有你了
so he could have you.
他怎么背叛你的
How did he betray you?
他安排了一个会面
He set a meeting.
我们本该讨论我的下一个任务
We were supposed to discuss my next assignment.
他没告诉我的是
What he didn't tell me
我们面见的是中情局的副局长
was that we were meeting a man named Harlan Gaines,
哈伦・盖恩斯
a deputy director of the CIA.
当时盖恩斯正在调查"21号空间"
Gaines was investigating 21-Void.
想查出幕后主使的那个叛徒是谁
Looking for the traitor behind it.
那时我才知道我的工作并非是由中情局批准的
That's when I knew my work wasn't sanctioned by the CIA.
波塞冬为了阻止调查
Poseidon shot and killed Gaines that night,
当晚就射杀了盖恩斯
to stop the investigation.
他让我去搬尸体
He told me to move the body,
掩盖所有痕迹
make it look like it never happened.
我看了那一部分的照片  他们都是假的
I've seen the photos of that part, they're damning.
他选了我搬运盖恩斯尸体的照片
He chose images that showed me moving Gaines' body,
删除了会给他自己定罪的那些照片
eliminated the ones that incriminated himself.
那时我知道我被下套了
I knew I was being set up.
他加强了对我的控制
He was tightening his control over me,
但我却无能为力
but there was nothing I could do.
至少他是这么想的
At least, that's what he thought.
当我知道波塞冬已经变节
When I knew Poseidon had gone rogue
以及违反中情局规定私自开展行动时
and was operating outside the CIA,
我就开始谋划回到你身边的事了
that's when I started my plan to get back to you.
你并没有啊
You're not.
另一个人盗用了你的...
Some other man has your--
你的脸  你的过去  你的整个人生
your face, your past, your whole life.
莎拉  我有个计划来纠正这一切
Sara, there is a plan to make this right,
来保护我们的家庭
to protect our family.
迈克尔  他现在和我们的儿子在一起
Michael, he's with our son right now.
他和麦克在一起
He's with Mike.
我... 听着  我得走了
I, uh, look, I have to go.
诺亚  你要给我们造艘船吗
Hey, Noah, you gonna build us a boat?
不  我会做件更赞的事
Nope. I'm gonna do one better.
你给谁打电话呢
Who you calling?
一个有船的朋友
A friend who actually has a boat.
喂
Hello?
-苏克雷  是我  -林肯吗
- Sucre, it's me. - Linc?
我还以为你会死在中东了  老兄
I thought the Middle East was gonna swallow you up, man.
迈克尔在哪  你找到他了吗
Where's Michael? Did you find him?
听着  这就是我为什么打电话
Listen, that's why I'm calling.
我们在克里特岛上
We're on the Island of Crete.
我们需要低调地坐船回美国
We need a low profile ride back to the States.
我是很想帮忙
I would love to help,
但我们现在在世界的另一端  兄弟
but we're on the other side of the world, brother.
我们刚在摩洛哥卸了货
We just dropped a load in Morocco.
你在说些什么啊  摩洛哥离克里特岛很近
What are you talking about? Morocco's near Crete.
是啊  我知道  当然是了
Yeah, I know, of course it is,
其实我的意思是这艘船不是我的
but what I mean is it's not my ship.
好吧  那么搭个顺路船要多少钱
Yeah, but what would it cost to hitch a ride?
你们不能随便上船
You can't hitch a ride.
你们必须租下整艘船
You have to rent the whole ship.
老板说五万美元一次  林肯
The boss charges 50K a leg, Linc.
你们想回美国  那就需要五万
You want to get back to the States, it's 50K.
五万吗
50k?
我们只是想回家
We're just trying to get home.
你知道我们没那么多现金
You know we don't have that kind of cash.
现在有了
You do now.
拿去  这个是我祖母的
Here, this was my grandmother's.
这件传家宝至少值那么多钱
It's an heirloom worth at least that.
我也想不出它还能派更好的用场了
I can't think of a better use for it.
谢谢你
Thank you.
我们有钱了  苏克雷  来克里特岛吧
We got it, Sucre. Get to Crete.
他不会伤害麦克的
He's not gonna hurt Mike,
除非他怀疑你知道他的真实身份了
not unless he suspects you know who he really is.
如果你戳穿他的伪装  他才会下狠手
If you remove his mask, he'll lash out.
你比我更了解他
You know him better than I do.
这正是关键  没人真正了解他
That's the point, no one knows him.
所以我该怎么做
So, what do I do?
你就陪他"演戏"  伪装好你自己
You play his game. You wear your own mask.
一旦你有机会带着麦克逃离
As soon as you get a chance to get away with Mike,
抓住时机  赶紧跑
you take it, disappear.
我会尽快赶到美国
I'll get to the States as soon as I can.
我会找到你们
I'll find you.
你看起来好多了
You're looking better.
头发变白了  但是好多了
A little grayer, but better.
我有一位随叫随到的好医生
I have an amazing doctor on call.
我会伪装自己  我会陪他演下去
I will wear the mask. I will play his game...
如果他伤害我们的儿子  我会杀了他
and if he hurts our son I'll kill him.
我不能...
I can't...
一定要回到我们身边
Please come back to us.
她准备一个人离开克里特岛
She's leaving Crete alone,
就是说她丢下了乌提斯  而他会跟着她
which means she left Outis behind, and he'll try to follow,
过一两天就会回到美国
return to the U.S. in the next day or two.
只可能是坐船或飞机
It can only be by ship or plane,
把他的照片发往所有海空频道
so plaster his face on all maritime and air channels,
重点检查未来48小时内从克里特岛离开的
focusing on all vessels departing from Crete
所有飞机船只
in the next 48 hours.
他肯定在其中之一上
He's got to be on one.
-不能让他回到美国  -雅各布
- He can't make it back inside the country. - Jacob?
是妈妈的电话吗
Was that Mommy?
是的  妈咪在回家的路上
Yes. Mommy's on her way home.
迈克尔·斯科菲尔德
Michael Scofield.
我的好兄弟  你的命比谁都多
My man, you got more lives than anyone.
换做是我  没准早把命都用光了
Think I might've used them all up.
真是只不死鸟啊
A damn phoenix.
真不敢相信
I can't believe it.
我想听你说
I want to hear every damn thing
在你诈死后发生的所有事
that's happened to you since you died.
兄弟  你还活着啊
Papi, you're alive?
那个船长是个见钱眼开的杂种
The skipper is a corrupt bastard.
少跟他来往  他货舱内有枪
Don't mess with him. He's got guns in the hold,
还有各种违禁品
all kinds of contraband.
船长
Captain.
这就是我跟你说的"货"
Here's the cargo I was telling you about.
付钱
Pay up.
五万在哪里
Where's the 50K?
这里
Here.
我说了要现金
I said cash.
这是颗蓝宝石  六克拉  完美无瑕
It's a sapphire, six carats, flawless,
周围是一圈2.5克拉的镶边钻石
surrounded by 2.5 carats of bezeled diamonds.
黑市价是十二万五千
Street value is 125K.
你可以按半价当了它  还能赚到钱
You can pawn it for half that and still make a profit.
如果这是假的  我就把你们扔到海里喂鱼
If it's fake, you go under the sea.
我最没想到的是会在船上找到你  老兄
A boat is the last place I expected to find you, buddy.
我原以为你讨厌水
I thought you hated the water.
没错  你还记得啊  但我有案底
Yeah, you remember, but I got a record.
很少有雇主愿意给我这个机会
Not a lot of employers lined up to take a chance on me.
再说  这艘船为我的副业
Besides, this ship provides opportunities
提供了便利
for my side business...
这才是我待在这艘船上的真正原因
...which is the real reason I'm on this boat.
这艘宝贝船里
This baby...
装了我这辈子的积蓄
...houses my entire life savings.
我跟你们说  这会是一大笔钱
I'm telling you, it's gonna be huge.
我再过几个月就能把这一切都抛在身后了
I'm a few months away from putting all this behind me.
要是你们走运  我会让你们
If you guys are lucky, I'll let you guys
带上我的一个"妞儿"爽一发
take one of my ladies for a spin.
什么  就是性爱娃娃吗
What, sex dolls?
不是  要有点品味啊  兄弟
No, have some class, man.
准确的说是可充气  高品质
The term is inflatables, high quality,
昂贵  逼真的 性爱娃娃
expensive, very lifelike.
亲爱的
Hey, honey.
你好啊
Hey, you.
麦克呢
Where's Mike?
睡了
Asleep.
孩子今天累坏了
Kid had a big day.
但最重要的是
Most important, though,
迈克尔怎么样了
how's Michael?
你帮到他了吗
Were you able to help him?
我到的时候  他已经奄奄一息了
I mean, he was barely alive when I got there.
他... 基本处于睡眠状态
He, uh, slept most of the time.
我为他尽力了  我...
I-I did what I could for him. I, uh...
让他的病情稳定了  但他变了
I stabilized him, but he's changed.
他... 不再是我认识的那个迈克尔了
He, uh... he's just not the guy I knew.
所以  他们送我到了机场  就这样了
‭So, they dropped me at the airport and that was that.
他们是谁
They?
林肯和另外一个人
Linc and some other guy.
麦克
Mike?
麦克呢
Where's Mike?
-你说他都睡了  -他是睡了
- You said that he was asleep. - ‭He is...
在朋友家  他去朋友家过夜了
at a friend's house, a sleepover.
好吧  哪个朋友
Okay. Which friend?
他在帕特里克家
He's at Patrick's house.
你祖母的戒指呢
What happened to your grandmother's ring?
我真是太笨了
I'm such an idiot.
去的路上怕弄丢所以摘下来了
I took it off on the way over for safekeeping,
我怕被偷了
'cause I didn't want it to get stolen,
结果再找的时候  发现不见了
then when I looked for it on the way back it was gone.
当时我大声尖叫  差点被人赶下飞机了
Screamed so loud they nearly threw me off the flight.
注意  此人极度危险
系ISIL恐怖分子
曾杀害一名中情局高级官员
并制造多起爆炸案
喂
Yeah?
五角大楼的人来了消息
We spoke to our man at the Pentagon.
刚收到海上警报
A naval alert just went out.
发现卡尼尔·乌提斯
Kaniel Outis has been located
在地中海一艘货船上
on a cargo ship in the Mediterranean.
是船长报告的
It was reported by the ship's captain.
海军打算怎么做
What's the navy gonna do about it?
最近的濒海战斗舰正驶向目标准备进攻
The nearest LCS combat craft is moving to engage.
已派出了海豹突击队
SEAL team's been deployed.
下的命令呢
Orders?
寻找并击毙卡尼尔·乌提斯
To seek and destroy Kaniel Outis.
很好
Good.
信息我们已经发出去了
We've done our job getting the message out.
现在就等海豹突击队完成任务了
Now it's time for the SEALs to do theirs.
天啊
My God.
你这一遭真是曲折  哥们
You've been through hell, my friend.
要有信念  伙计
Have some faith, papi.
谢谢  伙计
Thanks, papi.
你怎么样  林肯
What about you, Linc?
我觉得林肯有个秘密女友
I think Linc's got a secret girlfriend,
那位女飞行员
the pilot lady.
她不是我女朋友
She's not my lady.
不如让苏克雷给你搞下性爱娃娃
Maybe Sucre will set you up with one of his sex dolls.
她们不是娃娃  伙计
They're not dolls, man.
抱歉  充气娃娃
Sorry, inflatables.
我们换个话题吧
Look, let's just change the subject, please.
不如谈谈安顿下来的事
You know, might be something to be said for settling down.
好吧  没这张牌
Right, well... that's not in the cards.
从外面上了锁
It's locked from the outside.
他们识破你了
They made you.
你真的是个被通缉的恐怖分子
You really are a wanted terrorist.
那你以为他说的都是什么
What the hell did you think he was saying?
我还以为只是个比喻
I thought it was an analogy.
天啊
For God's sake.
这房间里没有其他出路
There's no other way out of this cabin.
所有船员都到甲板集合
All crew to the top deck. All hands up.
服从命令  否则我们会开枪射击
Comply or be fired on.
此船现已属于美国海军管辖
This ship is now under the control of the U.S. Navy.
准备登船
Prepared to be boarded.
追兵到了
We got company.
我建议跳船
I say we jump.
我们要游很长的距离
That's a long way down.
只有这条出路
It's the only way out.
太远了
It's too far.
我有个办法
I have an idea...
但得受点苦
...but it's gonna hurt.
莎拉
喂
Hello?
海瑟  是我  听着  现在不方便说
Hey, Heather, it's me. Listen, I can't talk,
但我需要你现在去接麦克  好吗
but I need you to go pick up Mike right now, okay?
你知道帕特里克·门罗家住哪吗
Do you know where Patrick Monroe lives?
知道
Yeah.
好的
Okay.
听着  我过后再解释
Listen, I'll explain later.
别把他带回来  好吗
Don't bring him back here, okay?
让他跟着你  我会尽快过去
Keep him with you. I'll be over as soon as I can.
你能帮我这个忙吗
Can you do that for me?
好  我现在就出门
Yeah. I'll leave right now.
没事吧
I-I-Is everything okay?
有事
No.
走
Go.
六个人  剩下跟我走
Six. The rest with me.
走
Go.
一  二  三  四
One, two, three, four.
走  走
Go, go.
我往左  你往右
I'll go left, you right.
他们从窗户出去了
They went out the window!
你看见什么了
What do you see?
没看到人
No visual.
A1小队  A2小队去左舷  快
Alpha One, Alpha Two to portside, now.
收到
Copy that.
行了
Okay!
把它... 把它拿掉
Take... Take it off!
你叫什么名字
What's your name?
费尔南多
Fernando.
费尔南多·苏克雷
Fernando Sucre.
我是船员  看看名册
I'm a member of this crew. Check the roster, man.
我和这事没关系
I got no part in any of this.
从名册里找费尔南多·苏克雷
Check the roster for Fernando Sucre.
此人似乎没有嫌疑
Suspect seems to check out.
把他带到驾驶舱上去
Take him to the bridge.
是  长官
Yes, sir.
走吧
Let's move.
绝对不许任何人下船  明白吗
Absolutely no one gets off this ship, understand?
是
Sir.
我不认识什么卡尼尔·乌提斯
I don't know any Kaniel Outis.
他叫斯科菲尔德
The guy's name is Scofield.
很多年没见过了
Haven't seen him in years.
他给我打电话  说需要我送他一程
He calls me, he says he needs a ride.
正在轮机层追捕嫌犯
We got active pursuit on engine deck.
看好他
Watch him.
他叫斯科菲尔德
The guy's name is Scofield!
苏克雷说的就是那扇门
That's the door Sucre told us about.
他们在那
There they are!
不许动  不许动
Freeze! Freeze!
快点  快点
Look alive, look alive!
他们无路可逃了
We've got them bottled up.
伙计们  快点  快点
Guys, come on! Hurry!
快点
Hurry!
卡住了
It's stuck!
快点  卡住了
Come on! ‭It's stuck!
卡住了
It's stuck!
把他们熏出来  快
Smoke them out, go!
催泪瓦斯弹
Tear gas.
如果进了通风系统  我的货就毁了
That hits the ventilation, it's gonna ruin my cargo.
你向来都是个废物  苏克雷
You've always been a loser, Sucre.
我雇过的最烂的船员
Worst shipmate I ever hired.
你把这人渣带到我的船上来
You brought this scum on board my ship.
他们是你的朋友  他们要去哪
They're your friends. Where are they going?
他们是熟人的熟人
They're associates of associates.
我很多年没见过他们了
I haven't seen them in years.
但你说到点子上了
But that's a good point.
不如你告诉这个面善的海豹突击队员
Why don't you tell the nice SEAL here
你是怎么收他们船票钱的
how you accepted payment for their passage?
可能他们是你的朋友  而不是我的
Maybe they're your friends, not mine.
好吧  好吧
Okay, okay.
我听到他们提到17号集装箱什么的
I heard them say something about container 17.
就是那个17号集装箱
That container 17.
就是装了你的绝密货物的那个  对吧
The one with your super secret cargo, huh?
武器弹药吧
Weapons and munitions?
文森特  目标可能获得武器
Vincent, tangos may be arming themselves.
如果他们发现武器肯定不会给你好脸色吧
Man, they're not gonna like you if they find that, are they?
文森特
Vincent.
你最终也可能上了针对恐怖分子的监视名单
You might just end up on the terrorist watch list, too.
文森特  听得到吗
Vincent, do you copy?
听不清楚
Can't read you.
毫无用处的墨西哥人  你算计好了的
Good-for-nothing Mexican. You planned this.
在这别动
Stay here.
17号还封着
17's still sealed.
船长
Captain?
哥可是波多黎各人
I'm Puerto Rican.
正前方  你们听到声音了吗
12 o'clock. You hear that?
快点
Come on!
快走  快走
Go, go. Move!
怎么回事
What's going on?
船改变航线了
The ship's changing course.
我做到了  兄弟
I did it, papi.
现在没有退路了
No going back now.
看看他们下一步怎么办
See what their next move is.
还记得我们的蜜月吗
Do you remember our honeymoon?
当然
Yeah, of course.
当时你向我敞开心扉
How you opened up.
跟我说你对在福克斯河监狱里做的事充满愧疚
Told me you carried shame for what you did at Fox River.
说你有时候都希望从来没听说过
How some days you wished you'd never heard
迈克尔·斯科菲尔德这个名字
the name Michael Scofield.
甚至  你还承认对我撒谎
Even admitted to lying,
对我隐瞒了这些事实
keeping it all from me.
当时的你最终向我坦白
How you finally came clean
并抛开一切过往
and put it all behind you?
没错
Sure.
我也原谅了你对我撒谎
I forgave you for the lies.
原谅了你的过去
Your past.
接受了你
Accepted you.
疼爱你和麦克
Loved you and Mike.
这些对你来说还不够吗
How is that not enough for you?
喂
Hi.
Hello?
我接到他了
I have him.
谢天谢地
Thank God.
他很好
He's fine.
正在回家的路上
Headed home now.
妈妈
Hi, Mom.
海瑟  感谢上帝
Heather, thank God.
我马上就到
I'll be there soon.
导航系统被破坏了
Navigation's been trashed,
控制器也损坏了
the controls damaged.
见鬼
Damn it.
货船偏离了航线
Tramp's off course.
正在全速往阿尔及利亚海域行进
Moving toward Algerian waters, top speed.
我们能修好它吗
Can we fix it?
需要花时间
It'll take time.
修好的时候肯定已经出公海了
And by then we'd be out of international waters.
呼叫猎鹰一号  请求指令
Falcon One requesting orders.
出现了问题
We have a situation.
讲
Yeah.
海豹突击队无法解决乌提斯
The SEAL team failed to neutralize Outis.
船的控制系统被损坏了
Somehow the ship's controls were damaged.
船正载着我们的士兵驶向阿尔及利亚海域
It's headed for Algerian waters with our soldiers on boards,
但是  如果他们继续完成任务
but it'll cause a diplomatic incident
一定会引起国际争端
if they stay to finish the job.
海军已经决定撤回突击队
The navy just made the call to pull the team.
好吧  好吧
All right, all right.
突击队解决不了  我们就加快行动速度
The SEALs couldn't do it. We escalate our move.
不应该小看了他们
Shouldn't have brought a knife to a gunfight.
我来负责以后的行动
I will handle from here.
谢谢
Thank you.
长官
Sir.
说
Yes.
我有一个十分紧急的请求
I have an ask, one that's imperative.
我相信  你会发现我们利益是一致的
I believe you'll find that our interests are aligned.
他们在干什么
What are they doing?
他们在撤离
They're leaving.
为什么
Why?
跑
Run!
天啊  不 不  不
Oh, God. No, no, no, no!
你会需要这个
You're gonna want this.
麦克很安全  你找不到了  这事结束了
Mike is safe where you can't touch him, and this is over.
你的生活  谎言  以及你的假面具
The life, the lies, the mask.
你都要如实地告诉我
You're gonna tell me everything.
比如说  你究竟是谁
Like who you really are,
这是怎么一回事  一切的一切
what this was, all of it.
这就是我们的生活
It was our life.
事情还没结束 莎拉
It's not over, Sara.
离结束还早着呢
Not even close.
麦克一直都没有危险
And Mike was never in danger.
我爱他
I love him.
他是我的家人
He is my family.
我养育了他
I raised him.
你又做了什么呢
What have you done?
不
No.
应该说  你做了什么  莎拉
It's what you've done, Sara.
这些事情本可以避免的
All of this could've been avoided.
晚上在朋友家过夜好玩吗
Good sleepover?
好玩
Yeah.
妈妈会来接我吗
Is Mommy coming to pick me up?
当然
Yes, sir.
迈克死定了
Michael's dead.
你去希腊的秘密旅行帮我找到了他
Your Nightingale trip to Greece led me straight to him.
所以  这都是你的错  莎拉
So... it's all on you, Sara.
你请海瑟帮忙的计划没有成功
And your plan with Heather didn't work.
我儿子呢
Where's my son?
在我手里
I have him.
至于我需不需要用他威胁你
And whether or not I have to threaten him--
虽然我也不想如此
which I don't want to do--
但这全看你要不要放下手里的枪了
is entirely contingent upon you putting the gun down.